Africa!
Tell you neighbour: Africa!
You don't regard and you don't respect your own.
I said, you don't regard and you don't respect your own.
I'm writing a book: "Africa, stop begging outside Africa".
We are beggars!
You never believe that you can go outside the country and bless them with the little you have
but you want to collect from them; this is why we are what we are - beggars.
I want to share with you one of my big secrets: All these crusades you see me doing all over the world -
Singapore, Indonesia, those big countries -
I pay 99% of the money.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When we are invited to crusade in America, Singapore,
I would say, "How much is the stadium?"
If the stadium is $100,000, I would say, "Do you have any area you want to support?"
They would say, "We are going to rent it". I would say, "No, you can't rent it for me.
For reasons known to me, we don't control the Holy Spirit.
Let me pray for whom God wants me to pray for.
Don't pay and start bringing your brother, sister, cousin or business man for prayer.
If you pay for the stadium for me, and you invite me for crusade,
you'll collect money from big business men that are sick, and those are the ones you will arrange in the front for prayer.
And you will now be telling me, "Pray for this person, don't pray for this person.
Don't pray for this one; this one - pray for him.
You have not prayed for this one, Man of God. He's the one that has payed 70% of the money.
God cannot cooperate or support such an arrangement.
Or you would be telling me that I should come out at 8 am,
when the Spirit of God is telling me I should come out at 10 am".
My accommodation - I don't let them know where I'm going to lodge.
After the crusade you can know where I'm living
but before or during the crusade I will not allow you to come to me.
You organiser, you cannot see me until after the crusade.
On the last day of the crusade I' would call them, "Follow me home.
I'm sorry for not showing you where I'm living".
I will enter your country with money,
and I will go out of the country and not take your money out of the country.
It's the rule and regulation because the grace is not for sale.
My joy is to see people healed, blessed and delivered; that is my money.
Each person that is delivered is more than $20,000.
Okay, imagine - in each crusade, almost 500 people get delivered.
500 times $20,000 - that is the money God is giving me.
$20,000 times 500.
You know that it is a huge amount of money, which is more than this money you are talking about.
The joy to sleep, joy.
You need to know what it means if God uses you to heal people.
If you knew what it means if God uses you to deliver people, you would want to deliver people all the time.
If you knew the joy in using you to deliver people,
you would never ask the people you deliver to bring kobo or money.
Anything. Even when they give you, you beg them, "Please, don't destroy my life!"
If you know what it is, brother, stand up. You are from where?
Zambia.
If you know what it is to set you free...
You are now here with a situation from Zambia.
If you know what it is to set you free from your problem...
Ha!
It's more than trillion dollars! Only you!
So if you know what it is to set people free, you would never...
Even after you have set a person free, don't wait for the person to greet you "thank you".
This "thank you", you don't need it. This is why after praying for you, I leave you.
I don't want you to say "thank you, sir".
I don't want that because God has given me something more than "thank you, sir".
I don't want anything to affect that "thank you, sir".
If God uses you to remove the pain of one, you are more than a millionaire.
You people believe that your reward is money.
No!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you know what it means to do something and collect money,
and that money is your gain,
you are robbing yourself.
Something insufficient and that money is what?
Insufficient! It cannot help you, it cannot give you peace.
Money can't give you peace; if money can give you peace, many of you would not be here today.
This is why you just see me at Ikotun Egbe since I started.
Branch - hmm.
From Ikotun Egbe to where? Look at glory of God.
Expansion of the grace can be dangerous if you are not careful.
If God gives you one dollar and that one dollar increases to 100 dollars,
it could be very dangerous.
That is why when the grace of God expands, you too have to be very careful.
Contain it. If you are no ready, hold it; you can know if you are not ready.
Like many of us - you do little business, millions of dollars enter your pocket.
Because you have millions of dollars, you establish many companies.
Will you be able to contain it, will you be able to hold it, will you be able to have power over this company?
Or you ministers of God - God called you as a minister, and you start.
You are gifted with message - powerful message.
When you are talking, people cry.
A lot of people keep trooping to your church.
Because of that, you suddenly anoint this one.
Stand up - you suddenly anoint this one because your church is growing.
Anoint this one - your church is growing - a big church.
Right. Okay, you go to Zambia.
Go and establish one.
You - go to Cotonou.
Go to London.
Go to America.
It could be dangerous.
Because of expansion.
You can't contain it.
If you know the expansion is becoming (big)...
That is it.
You may be seated, sir.
Yes.
When I started, the ministry was booming.
Branches here, branches there.
I just said, Please, can you close that branch for God's sake
because I know I would not be able to stand, even though there's great power".
But the human side of me -
I have no anointing to give you; it is God who anoints.
Suddenly in a hurry, because the church has grown, I anoint you.
Maturity needs time and experience.
No matter the mighty power God gives to you, you need to mature over time.
You can go up and come down again.
This is what has happened to many of us here -
you were up there one time but now you start again from here.
What kind of life is that? Why can't you take it easy
and go up in a season,
by obeying season - dry season, rain season.
Just go up by season.
But you go up and down again.
We serve God with our life.
Tell your neighbour: We serve God with our life.
But you believe you serve God with the Bible.
You read the Bible and you serve God with the Bible - "Jesus said this, Jesus said that".
You have forgotten your life.
You have to serve God with your life, not only with the Bible.
That's what the Bible says.
You seem to forget to serve God with your life.
Do you know that your life preaches better than your mouth?
If you are telling me, "Jesus is Lord. Jesus is Lord. Jesus is Lord" -
that one is not strong enough; let your life say it.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If I stand here and begin to tell you, "Jesus is Lord", "Jesus is Saviour", "Jesus is this", "Jesus is that"...
But your life can preach better - your life; mere looking at your life.
It can preach better.
A better sermon. Say, "My life can preach a better sermon".
I can't hear you.
My life can preach a better sermon.
So does your life preach? It is your mouth that preaches, not your life.
Look at me - without even talking.
If you just walk out and say, "Ok, who is this man?" You go on YouTube.
Look - I travelled to Israel. I was telling you people
that they were telling me I should not talk, that they know me.
They were telling me what I'm doing and they could see...
This is what they were talking about in Nazareth, Capernaum and all others.
I was glad; I was looking at them.
So that is my life. I didn't preach this time; my life preached to them.
God's time is the best.
What you have just seen -
whatever decision of God, I have no life of mine.
If the Lord says yes, who am I to say no?
God has a purpose of sending me to your midst.
There's a purpose for sending me to your midst.
Yes.
At the same time, there's a purpose of taking me to Israel.
Maybe God wants you to appreciate me and God of T.B. Joshua better.
By the time you want to see me, you have to pay for a ticket to fly to Israel.
I'm going there to see.
You will appreciate it better.
And you know, right from the beginning of this ministry,
it is the ministry that is the most persecuted in the world.
The most persecuted ministry.
Who are the people persecuting the ministry?
My people - Africa.
I take it back again.
This ministry is the most persecuted ministry in the world.
There's no name my people have not called,
and there's nothing they have not done.
Strange thing!
Who are the people?
My people - Africa!
It has not been an easy thing, if not God.
That is why I choose to live a lonely life.
If you want to see me, come to this church.
I don't go out; that is a lonely life.
It has not been easy because I don't know who is a friend and who is an enemy.
I don't know.
I would have loved to come to your wedding, your ceremony,
inviting me, sitting at the table, eating rice and chicken.
But I don't trust anyone anymore,
talkless of eating in your house.
But yet, I'm always in your midst; right from the beginning of the ministry.
Since thirty years of the ministry, I have always been with you people.
If I go for revival, after the revival, I come back.
I don't miss you peopie; I love you people.
Upon the prosecution and hatred, I decided to love you, to take the path of love.
You show hatred; I show love.
But I want to say something: I love you so much.
And I will always stand for the path of love.
Anytime you pray, remember Africa in prayer.
Many heroes, many great people - they have chased them out of Africa.
What has happened to me right from the beginning of this ministry is enough to chase me out of this country.
What has happened to me has never happened to any minister of God in this world.
Mention any minister of God it has happened to.
No.
In this world, no minister of God.
But I'm still in your midst.
There were enough to chase me out of Nigeria, Africa.
But I will go for revivals, and at the revivals, you will always see the stadium full.
The country, ministers - all of them gather.
But I am not carried away by that; after the crusade - back home.
Back to Africa where I am being persecuted,
where they want me to be killed, destroyed.
I live where I am not celebrated; I left the place where I am celebrated.
I'm celebrated all over the world but I left the place.
I'm living where I am not celebrated.
I want to pray with you. You put this thing behind you so we can move forward.
I'm only expressing the happening, the journey so far.
Okay.
Bow down your head and ask God to give you a hearing heart, in Jesus Christ's name.
Ask God to give you strength, so you will not give up.
Don't give up
Where you are not celebrated is the best place to stay, to get strength.
When you are in the midst of battle, you are building yourself; it's good.
Where you are not celebrated, where you are being persecuted is the best place for you to live.
It will build vou; all this will build you.
Gold cannot be gold without passing through the furnace.
Human character too needs to pass through the furnace.
That is why I decided to stay where I'm not celebrated - here in Nigeria, here in Africa.
I stayed there to build the grace of God.
When the grace of God is in the midst of challenges, it gets stronger.
So that is why I stayed in your midst.
Ask God to give you the grace to stay where you are not celebrated.